Prakash Parmar

React Front-End Developer

Phone: 8866808798

Address: Ahmedabad, Gujarat, India:

Website: https://pekskumar.github.io/Portfolio-React/

Email: prakash.montu_92@live.com

*PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I've been working from 2 year as a Frontend Developer. During that time I've been trained software platforms and systems. I have experience in **React js,** HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Jquery, Javascript and Bootstrap. I am Passionate about implementing and launching new projects. Looking to start the career as Full-Stack Frontend Developer with a reputed firm driven by technology.

* EXPERIENCES

April, 2022 -November, 2022

Front-End Engineer (React Js)

Acquaint Softtech Private Limited

- Expand features, refine code, and improve processes, producing smoother operations and enhancing user engagement.
- Designed dynamic and browser compatible pages using React js and npm packages, SCSS & CSS3, jQuery and Javascript.
- Collaborated with web designers, back end developers and UX designers to design, build, test and improve web products.
- I've experience in third party **REST API Integration** to scale up the **React SPA**, **React PWA** and **React SSR** Applications.
- Authentication and authorization using **react components** in web app.
- Ensured scalability of front end elements by optimizing them for loading speed and performance.
- Design web applications according to client briefs and modify designs to meet changes in client specifications.
- I also worked and hands on experience in wordpress web app development.

February, 2021 - April, 2022

Front-End Developer

CodeCaste Pvt Ltd

- Experience in Web Application Development in React JS Environment.
- Experience in Front-end react coding and deployment in a JavaScript Environment.
- Ability to write Effectively, clean, minimalistic, reusable **React js** code.
- Experience themes and builder in **WordPress** such as Avada, **Elementor**, DIVI, Visual Composer, Astra, Sydney and WPBakery etc.
- Developing customizing website using CBD in WordPress
- Designing fully customizing and pixel-perfect responsive website using Media Query and designing mobile-based features
- Handled multiple projects simultaneously while ensuring all projects were completed within the deadline date.
- Worked collaboratively with developers and in-house team to develop and maintain websites for a variety of clients.

June 2016 -October 2020

ST. XAVIER'S HIGHER SECONDARY SCHOOL

Computer Assistant Teacher

• Organize, maintain and manage class systems in proper working condition.

- Prepare execute lesson plans, assigning tasks, and evaluating student work and progress.
- Design and develop appropriate computer instructional material.
- Manage and monitor student behavior. Conduct group training sessions.
- Creating inventory and report files for computer Lab as monthly basis
- Designing and developing website for school and everyday updation and also handling google business account
- Doing office work like Aadhaar Enabled DISE online application form filling and making Students General Register book
- Making question paper for all subjects like Gujarati, Hindi, Sanskrit and English Languages
- Updating computer software programs and hardware components as needed.
- Install computer software programs and computer hardware and accessories.

* DESIGN & CODING

REACT JS

- SPA, PWA, SSR
- React Router
- React Component
- JSX Node + NPM
- Virtual DOM
- Ison
- Hooks
- map()
- Material UI
- AXIOS
- Redux-Saga(Basic)
- Rest Api

WEB DESIGN

- HTML5
- CSS3
- SCSS
- JAVASCRIPT
- JQUERY
- BOOTSTRAP
- XD
- FIGMA
- PHOTOSHOP

PHP CMS (WordPress)

- Theme Integration
- WordPress Plugins Integrate
- HTML Customization
- contact form7
- Gravity Forms
- WP File Manager
- Themes & Builder Avada, elementor, Divi, wpbakery, Visual Composer, etc.

* SKILL HIGHLIGHTS

- Web Development
- Cross Browser Operability
- Project management
- Process Improvement
- Workflow Optimization
- User Requirements Gathering

* PROJECTS

https://pekskumar.github.io/Prakash-SignUpFlow/Live Demo (Using React Js)

https://pekskumar.github.io/Portfolio-React/ Live Demo (Using React Js)

https://pekskumar.github.io/Prakash-Dashboard/ Live Demo (Using React Js)

https://pekskumar.github.io/Has-Websites-Reactjs-js/ Live Demo (Using React Js)

https://pekskumar.github.io/Has-Websites/ Live Demo (HTML, CSS, JQUERY, Javascript)

* SOCIAL ACCOUNT

Linked in

linkedin.com/in/pek-s-kumar-ba2636125

GitHub

https://github.com/Pekskumar

* EDUCATION

MCA [SEM-5]

L.J. Institute of Computer Applications(GTU)

BCA

St. Xavier's college(GU)

D.El.Ed.

NIOS (Govt. of India)

* CERTIFICATES

PHP (TOPS Technologies)

DCA [Shree Sahjanand Computer Center]

Tally 9 [Soni Academy Computer Training & Computer Education]

* AWARDS

Good Academic Grades Award

St. Xavier's College, Ahmedabad

* LANGUAGES

English

,

Gujarati

,

Hindi

* HOBBIES & INTERESTS

- Programming
- Travelling
- Designing
- Internet surfing
- Cricket
- Painting
- Reading books

* DECLARATION

I hereby certify that all the information provided here is correct to the best of my knowledge.